# **Chia-Hsiang Kao**

Email <a href="mailto:chkao.md04@nycu.edu.tw">chkao.md04@nycu.edu.tw</a>
Website <a href="https://iandrover.github.io">https://iandrover.github.io</a>

#### **Research Interests**

#### **Machine Learning & Computer Vision**

My goal is to develop robust and interpretable machine learning algorithms and systems that operate reliably even under challenging conditions. Along with my research goals, I am interested in meta-learning, self-supervised learning, model robustness, and explainable AI.

#### **Education**

#### **National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University (NYCU)**

Taipei, Taiwan

**Doctor of Medicine** 

Aug. 2015 - Jun. 2022

Overall GPA: 3.81/4.0, Major GPA: 3.82/4.0, CS-related GPA: 3.90/4.0

PS: National Yang Ming University (NYMU) and National Chiao Tung University merged in 2021. I originally studied at NYMU.

## **Publications**

MAML Is a Noisy Contrastive Learner in Classification | Paper | Poster | Github | ICLR'22, NeurlPS'21 Workshop Chia-Hsiang Kao, Wei-Chen Chiu, Pin-Yu Chen

- Proved that MAML belongs to supervised contrastive learning.
- Proposed a zeroing trick that significantly improves the convergence of MAML.

Demystifying T1-MRI to FDG18-PET Image Translation via Representational Similarity | Paper MICCAI'21 Chia-Hsiang Kao, Yong-Sheng Chen, Li-Fen Chen, Wei-Chen Chiu

• Hypothesized and verified that medical image translation models implicitly segment brain tissue types and identify brain regions.

Unravelling the Spatio-Temporal Neurodynamics of Rhythm Encoding-Reproduction Networks by a Novel fMRI Autoencoder | Paper NER'19

Chia-Hsiang Kao, Ching-Ju Yang, Li-Kai Cheng, Hsin-Yen Yu, Yong-Sheng Chen, Jen-Chuen Hsieh, Li-Fen Chen

• Proposed a novel auto-encoder to untangle the spatiotemporal patterns of neurodynamics. - Identified the rhythm encoding-reproduction networks of the brain.

# **Research Experiences**

## MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab

Massachusetts, USA

Research Student

Dec. 2020 - Aug. 2021, Jul. 22 - Aug. 2022

- Advisor: Dr. Pin-Yu Chen/ Co-advisor: Prof. Wei-Chen Chiu
- Proved that MAML is a supervised contrastive learning algorithm. Studied theories of self-supervised learning and adversarial learning.

# Brain Mapping Laboratory, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Student

Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2020

- Advisor: Prof. Li-Fen Chen
- Utilized explainable AI tools to understand the inner behavior of image translation models. Analyzed fMRI, MRI, and CT data and built various predictive models.

#### Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Student

Jun. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Advisor: Prof. Meng-Chang Chen
- Analyzed air quality data and built air pollution predictive models.

# **Clinical Experiences**

## Taipei Veteran General Hospital

Taipei, Taiwan

Intern Doctor

Oct. 2019 - Sep. 2020 , Jan. 2022 - Jun. 2022

• Served as a second-year intern doctor in Internal Medicine, Surgery, Pediatrics, OB/GYN, ICU, Emergency Medicine, Family Medicine, etc. I was responsible for the primary care of the inpatient in those departments.

Chi Mei Medical Center

Tainai, Taiwan

Nov. 2021 - Dec. 2021

• Served as an intern doctor in Internal Medicine and Emergency Medicine.

# Fellowships and Awards

Student Travel Award, MICCAI'21: To first author student with the highest scoring
 Undergraduate Research Fellowship, National Science and Technology Council, Taiwan
 2021

• Summer Research Fellowship, National Health Research Institutes, Taiwan

2018

#### **Skills & Others**

Paper ReviewComputer Vision and Image Understanding, AutoML'22, NeurIPS'21 WorkshopLanguagesMandarin (Native); English (Fluent, TOEFL 106/120)ProgrammingPython, JavaScript, MatlabLibrariesTensorFlow, Keras, Jax, PyTorch, OpenCV, Scikit-learnInterestsWriting, Reading, Travel, Swimming, Backpacking, Jogging